Eamon Grennan papers, 1964-2010
Emory University
- Diaries, 1962-2008, Series 4; Boxes 58 - 75
  The series consists of 171 diaries kept by Grennan from 1962-2008. The diaries are of a personal nature and consist primarily of Grennan's thoughts and reflections. There is a minimal amount of poetry included in the volumes. Grennan titled many of his early diaries and these titles are included when present. Grennan also numbered his diaries; numbers appear in brackets following the date or title of the journal. According to notes supplied by Grennan, diary number 96 was lost on a train.
  - No date, loose papers found in boxes with journal (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - 1962 June (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - 1964 October-1965 October 17 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - 1968 September-August 15, "Hair Raisers," "Mind Spliters," and "Bits and Scraps" [1-2] (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - 1969 August-November 21, "Day in, Day out" and "The Maze, The Minotaur, The Thread" [3-4] (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - 1969 November 22-1970 January 20, "The Maze, The Minotaur, The Thread" [5-6] (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - 1970 January-February 14, "The Maze, The Minotaur, The Thread" [7-8] (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - 1970 March 25-May 25, "The Maze, The Minotaur, The Thread" [9-10] (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - 1970 May 26-June 13, "The Maze, The Minotaur, The Thread" [11-12] (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - 1970 July 2-July 13, "The Maze, The Minotaur, The Thread Goes to Greece" [13] (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - 1970 July 18-August 12, "The Maze, The Minotaur, The Thread" [14-15] (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - 1970 September 7-December 20, "The Maze, The Minotaur, The Thread" [16-17] (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - 1970 December 21-1971 March 22, "The Maze, The Minotaur, The Thread" [18-19] (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - 1971 March 23-June 27, "The Maze, The Minotaur, The Thread" [20-21] (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - 1971 June 28-November 28, "The Maze, The Minotaur, The Thread" [22-23] (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - 1971 November 30-1972 March 14, "The Maze, The Minotaur, The Thread" [24-25] (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - 1972 May 15-September 19, "The Maze, The Minotaur, The Thread" and "Maze" [26-27] (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - 1972 September 20-1973 March 18, "Maze" [28-29] (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - 1973 March 23-August 29, "Maze" [30-31] (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - 1973 August 31-1974 February 18, "Maze" [32-33] (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - 1974 February 26-August 27, "Maze" [34-35] (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - 1974 September 5-1975 November 4 [36-37] (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - 1975 November 20-1977 December 6 [38-39] (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - 1976-1980, "Book of Nature" (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - 1977 December 7-1978 May 4 [40-41] (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - 1978 May 7-October 18 [42-43] (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - 1978 October 20-1979 October 15 [44-45] (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - 1979 November 18-1980 September 6 [46-47] (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - 1980 September 6-October 30, "Rome" and "Venice" [48-49] (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - 1980 October 30-1981 February 10, "Venice-Renvyle" [50-51] (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - 1981 February 11-May 1, "Renvyle-Dublin" [52-53] (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - 1981 May 2- September 15, "Dublin-Poughkeepsie" [54-55] (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - 1981 September 17-1982 January 8 [56-57] (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - 1982 January 10-April 1 [58-59] (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - 1982 April 5-July 3 [60-61] (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - 1982 July 5-December 13 [62-63] (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - 1982 December 19-1983 May 30 [64-65] (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - 1983 June 1-1984 June 25 [66-68] (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - 1984 June 26-1985 February 11 [69-70] (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - 1985 February 15-September 7 [71-72] (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - 1985 September 8-1986 June 28 [73-74] (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - 1986 July 1-1987 February 1 [75-76] (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - 1987 February 4-August 25 [77-78] (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - 1987 August 26-1988 June 13 [79-80] (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - 1988 June 14-1989 April 13 [81-83] (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - 1989 August 3-November 26 [84-85] (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - 1989 December 7-1990 July 18 [86-87] (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - 1990 July 22-1991 February 1 [88-89] (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - 1991 February 2- April 29 [90] (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - 1991 April 29-July 24 [91] (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - 1991 July 24-October 26 [92] (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - 1991 October 30-1992 March 11 [93] (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - 1992 March 13-July 13 [94] (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - 1992 July 4-November 2 [95] (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - 1993 March 11-May 21 [97] (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - 1993 May 31-August 4 [98] (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - 1993 August 4-November 6 [99] (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - 1993 November 8-1994 April 13 [100] (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - 1994 April 14-August 8 [101-102] (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - 1994 August 9-1995 February 4 [103-104] (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - 1995 February 5-June 26 [105-106] (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - 1995 June 27-September 9 [107] (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - 1995 September 9-November 22 [108-109] (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - 1995 November 22-1996 January 7 [110] (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - 1996 January 7-March 25 [111-112] (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - 1996 March 27-July 4 [113-114] (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - 1996 July 4-November 5 [115-116] (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - 1996 November 6-1997 January 11 [117-118] (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - 1997 February 6-April 23 [119-120] (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - 1997 April 23-August 21 [121-122] (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - 1997 August 23-1998 January 24 [123-124] (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - 1998 January 26-June 24 [125] (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - 1998 June 25-1999 January 9 [126] (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - 1999 January 9-July 26 [127-129] (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - 1999 July 26-December 18 [130-131] (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - 1999 December 20-2000 March 23 [132-133] (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - 2000 March 23-July 17 [134-135] (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - 2000 July 17-October 23 [136-137] (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - 2000 October 28-2001 March 21 [138-139] (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - 2001 March 22-July 21 [140-141] (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - 2001 July 22-2002 February 14 [142-143] (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - 2002 February 15-July 3 [144] (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - 2002 July 3-November 13 [145] (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - 2002 November 14-2003 February 6 [146] (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - 2003 February 7-June 25 [147-148] (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - 2003 June 26-September 28 [149-150] (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - 2003 October 6-2004 January 9 [151] (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - 2004 January 9-April 13 [152] (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - 2004 April 14-July 7 [153] (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - 2004 July 7-September 30 [154] (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - 2004 September 30-2005 January 12 [155] (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - 2005 January 12-April 4 [156] (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - 2005 May 4-July 22 [158] (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - 2005 July 24-September 26 [159] (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - 2005 October 31-2006 March 28 [161-162] (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - 2006 March 29-June 15 [163] (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - 2006 June 15-September 15 [164] (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - 2006 September 16-December 12 [165] (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - 2006 December 14-2007 April 4 [166] (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - 2007 April 5-July 24 [167] (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - 2007 July 25-December 31 [168] (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - 2008 July 1-May 18 [169] (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - 2008 May 20-August 14 [170] (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - 2008 August 15-December 1 [171] (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - 2008 December 31-2009 April 13 [172] (Box 75, Folder 5)
- Printed material, 1943-2010, Series 5; Boxes 76 - 80
  The series consists of printed material relating to Grennan, including printed material by Grennan, printed material about Grennan, material about Grennan's readings and appearances, and various other printed material. Printed material by Grennan primarily consists of published articles, essays, and reviews written by the poet. Printed material about Grennan consists of published articles, essays, interviews, reviews, and clippings written by others about Grennan's life and work. The series also includes flyers and programs relating to Grennan's readings and public appearances. Other printed material includes published works by other authors (often with inscriptions to Grennan), clippings relating to topics of interest to Grennan, and works translated by Grennan.
  Arranged in alphabetical and chronological order.
  - Printed material by Grennan
  - Article, "Andrea Zanzotto: Stellar and Homely, Patrick Barron: Recipient of the Raiziss/de Palchi Book Prize," American Poet, 2008 (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Article, "Author Feature," Teaching English Magazine, Summer 2008 (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Article, "Leaving Cert Novels-II 'The Old Man and the Sea,'" May 1 1982 (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Article, "Leaving Cert Poetry Yeats," The Irish Times, December 1983 (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - Article, "What I'm Reading," The Sunday Tribune, August 2000 (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Article, "Yeats, William Butler," Academic American Encyclopedia, 1980 (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - Book cover of What Light There Is, Gallery Books, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - Essay, "Arm and Sleeve: Nature and Custom in The Comedy of Errors," Philological Quarterly, 1980 (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - Essay, "Chosen Home: The Poetry of Peter Fallon," Éire-Ireland, Summer 1994 (Box 76, Folder 9)
  - Essay, "Figures in a Landscape: The Short Stories of Seumas O'Kelly," Studies: An Irish Quarterly Review, Autumn 1967 (Box 76, Folder 10)
  - Essay, "'Identity to Seek': The Selves of Emily," Green Mountain Review, Spring/Summer 2006 (Box 76, Folder 11)
  - Essay, "Keats' Contemptus Mundi: A Shakespearean Influence on the 'Ode to a Nightingale,'" Modern Language Quarterly, September 1975 (Box 76, Folder 12)
  - Essay, "'Prologues to What Is Possible': Coming to (Some) Terms with Stevens," Green Mountain Review, Winter 2009/2010 (Box 76, Folder 13)
  - Essay, "A Slight Companionable Ghost': Trying to Catch Sight of Yeats's Mother," Philocetetes, summer 2008 (Box 76, Folder 14)
  - Essay, "Telling the Trees from the Wood: Some Details of As You Like It Re-examined," English Literary Renaissance, Spring 1977 (Box 76, Folder 15)
  - Essay, "'This Story Shall the Good Man Teach His Son': Henry V and the Art of History," Papers on Language and Literature, Fall 1979 (Box 76, Folder 16)
  - Essay, "View from the Bridge: Irish Writing, 1977-78," Éire-Ireland, Fall 1978 (Box 76, Folder 17)
  - Essay, "What I Heard There," Metre, Spring/Summer 2000 (Box 76, Folder 18)
  - Essay, "The Women's Voice in Othello: Speech, Song, Silence," Shakespeare, Autumn 1987 (Box 76, Folder 19)
  - Introduction to "Eleven Irish Poets," Verse, 1986 (Box 76, Folder 20)
  - Introduction to Seumas O'Kelly, A Land of Loneliness and Other Stories, January 1969 (Box 76, Folder 21)
  - Letter, "Approving Praise," Hudson Valley, 1996 (Box 76, Folder 22)
  - Letter, "Instead of an Essay," The Stony Thursday Book, 1978 (Box 76, Folder 23)
  - Letter, "Studying John McGahern," no date (Box 76, Folder 24)
  - Poems, 18/3-30/4, no date (Box 76, Folder 25)
  - Poems, A-C, no date (Box 76, Folder 26)
  - Poems, D-G, no date (Box 76, Folder 27)
  - Poems, H-L, no date (Box 76, Folder 28)
  - Poems, M-Q, no date (Box 76, Folder 29)
  - Poems, R-T, no date (Box 76, Folder 30)
  - Poems, U-Z, no date (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Report of Judge, W.B. Yeats Society of New York, Poetry Competition, 1995-1999 (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Reviews, "Bejoyces," review of Index of Recurrent Elements in James Joyce's 'Ulysses,' by William M. Schute, James Joyce and Modern Literature edited by W.J. McCormack and Allistar Stead, and James Joyce: An International Perspective edited by Suheil Badi Bushrui and Bernard Benstock, August 1982 (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Reviews, "Casting a Cold Eye," review of Giacomo Leopardi: Moral Tales translated by Patrick Creagh, March 1984 (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - Reviews, "Coaxing a world into plain view," review of Spindrift by Vona Groarke, The Irish Times, October 17 2009 (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - Reviews, "Cock Robin," review of Bawdy Verse and Folksongs edited by Robert Burns, August 27, 1983 (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Reviews, "The Community and the Individual," review of The Lundys Letter by Gerald Dawe and The Berlin Wall Café by Paul Duncan, 1986 (Box 77, Folder 7)
  - Reviews, "Crazy Poets, Crazy Age," review of Manic Power: Robert Lowell and his Circle by Jeffrey Meyers, The Irish Times, September 26, 1987 (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - Reviews, "Cross-References," review of Short History of Anglo-Irish Literature, from its Origins to the Present Day by Roger McHugh and Maurice Harmo, July 17, 1982 (Box 77, Folder 9)
  - Reviews, "Energy and Commitment," review of The Ordinary House of Love by Theo Dorgan, Poetry Ireland Review, September 1991 (Box 77, Folder 10)
  - Reviews, "Fantasy Echo: Oracles, Enigmas," review of Through One Tear by Edward Nobles and Candy Necklace by Cal Bendient, no date (Box 77, Folder 11)
  - Reviews, "Free Speech," review of Ferocious Alphabets by Denis Donoghue, The Irish Times, November 28, 1991 (Box 77, Folder 12)
  - Reviews, "Grace Notes," review of The Harper's Turn by Tome MacIntyre, August 1982 (Box 77, Folder 13)
  - Reviews, "Heartfelt Poems of our Planetary Home," review of The Bones of Creation by Patrick Deeley and Tribe by Mary Montague, 2008 (Box 77, Folder 14)
  - Reviews, "A Jew from Prague," review of The Nightmare of Reason: A Life of Franz Kafka by Ernst Pawel, no date (Box 77, Folder 15)
  - Reviews, "Living Speech," review of The Penguin Book of Irish Verse: Second Edition edited by Brendan Kennelly, The Irish Times, July 1981 (Box 77, Folder 16)
  - Reviews, "Lovely Reticence," review of History and Promise: Poems from Laois by Pat Boran, Poetry Ireland Review, Summer 1991 (Box 77, Folder 17)
  - Reviews, "A Meeting of History and Mystery," review of Irish University Review: Eiléan Ní Chuilleanáin, July 21, 2007 (Box 77, Folder 18)
  - Reviews, "Monologues, Airs and Graces," review of Painting the Pink Roses Black by Gerard Smyth, Antarctica by Derek Mahon, and High Time by Derek Mahon, The Irish Times, 1986 (Box 77, Folder 19)
  - Reviews, "Mortal Lights," review of Courtyards in Delft by Derek Mahon, The Irish Times, March 28, 1981 (Box 77, Folder 20)
  - Reviews, "Old News," review of The Oxford Book of Traditional English Verse edited by Frederick Woods, July 1983 (Box 77, Folder 21)
  - Reviews, "Once Upon a Time," review of Piper at the Gates of Dawn: Wisdom of Children's Literature by Jonathan Cott, no date (Box 77, Folder 22)
  - Reviews, "Places in the Mind," review of Whereabouts by Mark Roper and New and Selected Poems by James J. McAuley, no date (Box 77, Folder 23)
  - Reviews, "A Poet Anchored in Childhood Landscapes," review of The Year of the Knif e by Philip Casey, Muscle Creek by Rosita Boland, Abigail Brown by Heather Brett, and Angle of Patrick's Hill by Richard Kearney, no date (Box 77, Folder 24)
  - Reviews, "A Poet and Translator," review of Michael Harnett: Collected Poems Volume 2, The Irish Times, 1987 (Box 77, Folder 25)
  - Reviews, "A Pre-eminent Poet of her Time," review of The Sun-Fish by Eiléan Ní Chuilleanáin, The Irish Times, December 12, 2009 (Box 77, Folder 26)
  - Reviews, "Shadow Among the Stars," review of Songs of the Psyche by Thomas Kinsella and Her Vertical Smile by Thomas Kinsella, The Irish Times, October 1984 (Box 77, Folder 27)
  - Reviews, "Still Wayfaring," review of Robert Lowell, Collected Poems edited by Frank Bidart and David Gewater, Poetry Ireland Review, Winter 2003/2004 (Box 77, Folder 28)
  - Reviews, "Trades-people," review of The Go Situation by Michael Foley, Rites and Mediations by Paul Murray, The Flower Master by Medbh McGuckian, and The Younger Irish Poets by Gerald Dawe, July 1982 (Box 77, Folder 29)
  - Reviews, "Uncommon Prayer," review of The New Oxford Book of Christian Verse edited by Donald Davie, The Irish Times, October 31, 1981 (Box 77, Folder 30)
  - Reviews, Untitled review of King John: New Perspectives edited by Deborah T. Curren Aquino, Shakespeare Quarterly, Spring 1991 (Box 77, Folder 31)
  - Reviews, Untitled review of The Outsiders: Poets of Contemporary Ireland by Frank Kersnowski, Éire-Ireland, Winter 1976 (Box 77, Folder 32)
  - Reviews, Untitled review of Rumours by Seamus Done, Poems in English by Michael Hartnett, Corca Bascinn by James Liddy, Verifications by Roy McFadden, Windfalls by Adian Carl Matthews, Mules by Paul Muldoon, A Store of Candles by Frank Ormsby, and World Without End by Gerard Smyth, Irish University Review, Spring/Summer 1978 (Box 77, Folder 33)
  - Reviews, "Who loses and who wins, who's in, who's out," review of The Harvill Book of Twentieth-Century Poetry edited by Michael Schmidt, The Irish Times, September 11, 1999 (Box 77, Folder 34)
  - Short story, "Roscera College in 2,000 A.D.," The Vexillum, Easter 1956 (Box 77, Folder 35)
  - Printed material about Grennan
  - Advertising blurbs, 1987-2011 (Box 77, Folder 36)
  - Article, "Distillation of Life: Poetry's Still Got the Beat" by Kristen Charles, Dutchess, March/April 2005 (Box 77, Folder 37)
  - Article, "Eamon Grennan Biographical Information," no date (Box 77, Folder 38)
  - Article, "Grennan," published in Infotrac, accessed by Ann Yarmal, September 1998 (Box 77, Folder 39)
  - Article, "Guest Editor: Eamon Grennan," published in Poetry Pilot, January 1988 (Box 77, Folder 40)
  - Article, "In the 'Cosmic Kitchen' with Poet Eamon Grennan," Vassar Views, October 1994 (Box 77, Folder 41)
  - Article, "Indelible Ireland" by Grant Condon, Northeast the Hartford Courant Sunday Magazine, June 1999 (Box 77, Folder 42)
  - Article, "A Migration" by Paul Weideman, The New Mexican, February 2008 (Box 77, Folder 43)
  - Clippings, no date (Box 77, Folder 44)
  - Clippings, 1992-2008 (Box 77, Folder 45)
  - Essay, "The 'Common Ground' of Eamon Grennan" by Deborah Fleming, Éire-Ireland, Winter 1993 (Box 77, Folder 46)
  - Essay, "Decaying Flesh and Human Transcendence in Eamon Grennan's Poetry" by Gordan Grant, Nua: Studies in Contemporary Irish Writing, 1998-1999 (Box 77, Folder 47)
  - Essay, "Vermeer in Verse: Eamon Grennan's Domestic Interiors" by Mary Fitzgerald-Hoyt, New Hibernia Review, Spring 1991 (Box 77, Folder 48)
  - Honors, Guggenheim Fellowship, 1994 (Box 77, Folder 49)
  - Honors, Lemore Marshal Poetry Prize, 2003-2004 (Box 77, Folder 50)
  - Honors, Los Angeles Times Book Prize Nominee, 1990 (Box 77, Folder 51)
  - Interview, "Celebrating Relations: An Interview with Eamon Grennan" by John Hobbs, Irish Literary Supplement, Fall 1998 (Box 77, Folder 52)
  - Interview, "Eamon Grennan" by Justin Quinn, Metre, Spring 2001 (Box 77, Folder 53)
  - Interview, "Eamon Grennan Interview" by Cara Cotter, Quadrangle, 2007 (Box 77, Folder 54)
  - Interview, "Eamon Grennan, Interview with Ben Howard" by Ben Howard, The Courtland Review, August 2000 (Box 77, Folder 55)
  - Interview, "The Shock of the Object" by Catherine Phil MacCarthy, Poetry Ireland Review, Winter 2006/2007 (Box 77, Folder 56)
  - Interview, "Um Irlandês com Poemas Americanos" by Ana Paula Guimarãs, Ler, Summer 1991 (Box 77, Folder 57)
  - Interview, "When Language Fails: An Interview with Eamon Grennan" by William Walsh, Kenyon Review, Summer 2006 (Box 77, Folder 58)
  - Reviews of As If It Matters, 1991-1993 (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Reviews of Facing the Music: Irish Poetry in the Twentieth Century, 2000 (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Reviews of Leopardi: Selected Poems, 1997 (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Reviews of Matter of Fact, 2008-2009 (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - Reviews of Out of Breath, 2007-2008 (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Reviews of The Quick of It, 2005-2006 (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Reviews of Relations: New and Selected Poems, 1998-2000 (Box 78, Folder 7)
  - Reviews of Selected and New Poems, 2000-2001 (Box 78, Folder 8)
  - Reviews of So It Goes, 1995-1997 (Box 78, Folder 9)
  - Reviews of Still Life with Waterfall, 2002-2004 [includes some editorial correspondence] (Box 78, Folder 10)
  - Reviews of Turning Tides: Modern Dutch and Flemish Verse in English Versions by Irish Poets, 1994 (Box 78, Folder 11)
  - Reviews of What Light There Is, 1987-1990 [includes some editorial correspondence] (Box 78, Folder 12)
  - Reviews of Wildly for Days, 1983 (Box 78, Folder 13)
  - Readings and appearances by Grennan
  - No date, March 1, Eamon Grennan, Ithaca College, Ithaca, New York (Box 78, Folder 14)
  - No date, April 12, Conversations with Eamon Grennan (Box 78, Folder 15)
  - No date, April 29, "Leopardi in English," Italian Studies at Tufts University, Medford, Massachusetts (Box 78, Folder 16)
  - 1986 September 16, Poets, Playwrights, Essayists, Editors, Novelists [PEN] New Writers' Evening, PEN American Center, New York, New York (Box 78, Folder 17)
  - 1988 July 29, The Poet Joyce, The James Joyce Annual Summer School, Department of Anglo-Irish Literature, University College Dublin, Dublin, Ireland (Box 78, Folder 18)
  - 1989 April 27, A Reading of Poems, W.B. Yeats: A Commemoration, Vassar College, Poughkeepsie, New York (Box 78, Folder 19)
  - 1990 January 10, New Poets: England and Ireland James Lasdun and Eamon Grennan, Poetry Society of America, New York, New York (Box 78, Folder 20)
  - 1990 April 4, 13th Annual Literary Festival, College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, Virginia (Box 78, Folder 21)
  - 1991 April 17, Eamon Grennan, Poetry Ireland, Dublin, Ireland (Box 78, Folder 22)
  - 1992 March 23, The Tenth Muse II, A Series of Readings by New Poets, Poetry Center of 92nd Street Y, New York, New York (Box 78, Folder 23)
  - 1992 May 11, "'Little Room': Bloom and the Politics of Space," 10th Annual Julian B. Kaye Lecture in James Joyce Studies, Ethyle R. Wolfe Institute for the Humanities and the Department of English at Brooklyn College of the City University of New York, Brooklyn, New York (Box 78, Folder 24)
  - 1993 April 13, Irish Poets in America, Kathryn Bache Miller Theatre at Colombia University, New York, New York (Box 78, Folder 25)
  - 1993 April 23, Reading Series, New York University Creative Writing Program, New York, New York (Box 78, Folder 26)
  - 1995 February 17, Howard County Poetry and Literature Society present Terence Winch meets Eamon Grennan, Columbia, Maryland (Box 78, Folder 27)
  - 1995 December 4, An Evening of Irish Poetry: with Paul Durcan, Eamon Grennan, and Eiléan Ní Chuilleanáin, 92nd Street Y, Tisch Center for the Arts, and Unterberg Poetry Center, New York, New York (Box 78, Folder 28)
  - 1995 December 7, Great Contemporary Poets read works in honor of the 50th Anniversary of the United Nations, United Nations Staff Recreation Council [UNSRC] Society of Writers and Permanent Mission of Ireland to the United Nations, New York, New York (Box 78, Folder 29)
  - 1996 April 20, Poetry in the Branches, Poets House and New York Public Library, New York, New York (Box 78, Folder 30)
  - 1997 March 4, Readings and Conversations, Lannan Foundations, Los Angeles, California (Box 78, Folder 31)
  - 1997 April 14, Drop Everything and Read, St. Agnes Branch Library, New York, New York (Box 78, Folder 32)
  - 1998 April 1, Eamon Grennan, Cultural Programs Committee at Manchester Community-Technical College, Manchester, Connecticut (Box 78, Folder 33)
  - 1998 April 2, Poetry Reading by Eamon Grennan, Associates of Swarthmore College Libraries, Swarthmore, Pennsylvania (Box 78, Folder 34)
  - 1998 October 18, Hear the "Poet's Voice" of Eamon Grennan, Horce E. Manacher Poetry Fund and Friends of Greenwich Library, Greenwich, Connecticut (Box 78, Folder 35)
  - 1999 May 4, Gaelic in Translation, Poets, Playwrights, Essayists, Editors, and Novelists [PEN] Translation Committee and Ireland House at New York University, New York, New York (Box 78, Folder 36)
  - 1999 June 9, Season 8 of Sunken Garden Poetry Festival, Hill-Stead Museum, Farmington, Connecticut (Box 78, Folder 37)
  - 1999 October 28, Writers Harvest: The National Reading, New York University Creative Writing Program Reading Series, New York, New York (Box 78, Folder 38)
  - 2000 February 24, Poetry Reading by Eamon Grennan, Coiste Ealaíne an Chaisleán Nua Thiar, Newcastle West, Ireland (Box 78, Folder 39)